<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on BN</title>
    <link>https://nobleator.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on BN</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nobleator.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>EML File Generation</title>
      <link>https://nobleator.github.io/2021/01/eml-file-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nobleator.github.io/2021/01/eml-file-generation/</guid>
      <description>EML files can be a handy way to create an email message without requiring an actual mail server, as it is simply a file format. You can create these files by hand, but there are some easy mistakes to make. For instances, you need to include newlines in very particular places to successfully generate an EML file.
Invalid EML From: Alice &amp;lt;alice@example.com&amp;gt;To: Bob &amp;lt;bob@example.com&amp;gt;Subject: Testing 123Date: 1 Jan 2000 12:00:00Content-Type: text/plain; charset=UTF-8;Hello World!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASOIAF Miniatures Calculator</title>
      <link>https://nobleator.github.io/2021/01/asoiaf-miniatures-calculator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nobleator.github.io/2021/01/asoiaf-miniatures-calculator/</guid>
      <description>Description This is a calculator used to graph probabilities for various attack combinations for the A Song Of Ice and Fire Miniatures Game. This is a tabletop wargame based in G.R.R. Martin&amp;rsquo;s fantasy world where 2-4 (usually just 2) players build armies from different factions then compete to win a certain number of victory points. There are different game modes that determine how to achieve VPs, but generally killing your opponent&amp;rsquo;s troops will help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Mechanics</title>
      <link>https://nobleator.github.io/2020/10/game-mechanics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nobleator.github.io/2020/10/game-mechanics/</guid>
      <description>Engine builders This is a mechanic where each player builds up power over time, creating an engine that feeds itself and allows for more powerful tools to be added over time. The classic example of this is Dominion, where you build your deck by drafting from a shared marketplace of cards to build their individual decks. Another example would be Lords of Waterdeep, where you can build up &amp;ldquo;shops&amp;rdquo; over time which then grant you more resources as other players use them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
