<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>programming on nobleator</title>
    <link>/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in programming on nobleator</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Secret Santa Assigner</title>
      <link>/posts/secret-santa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/secret-santa/</guid>
      <description>Description This is a tool I wrote to help plan our Secret Santa assignments each year for Christmas. There are a couple of requirements:
 You should not be paired with your significant other You should not be paired with the same person you had last year You should not be paired with the same person who is paired with you this year  Design I considered using a more elaborate solution with select boxes for the significant other and last year participant columns, but those are not supported in vanilla HTML tables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Murder Mystery</title>
      <link>/posts/sql-murder-mystery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/sql-murder-mystery/</guid>
      <description>Description Someone at the Northwestern University Knight Lab put together a fun little murder mystery puzzle that requires you to use SQL to solve it SQL Murder Mystery. It&amp;rsquo;s also nice that you can run your queries directly in the browser, so no need to install anything to get going.
Solution Here is the path I took while solving this mystery. Given the starting information &amp;ldquo;the crime was a ​murder​ that occurred sometime on ​Jan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EML File Generation</title>
      <link>/posts/eml-file-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/eml-file-generation/</guid>
      <description>EML files can be a handy way to create an email message without requiring an actual mail server, as it is simply a file format. You can create these files by hand, but there are some easy mistakes to make. For instances, you need to include newlines in very particular places to successfully generate an EML file.
Invalid EML From: Alice &amp;lt;alice@example.com&amp;gt;To: Bob &amp;lt;bob@example.com&amp;gt;Subject: Testing 123Date: 1 Jan 2000 12:00:00Content-Type: text/plain; charset=UTF-8;Hello World!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASOIAF Miniatures Calculator</title>
      <link>/posts/asoiaf-minis-calc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/asoiaf-minis-calc/</guid>
      <description>Description This is a calculator used to graph probabilities for various attack combinations for the A Song Of Ice and Fire Miniatures Game. This is a tabletop wargame based in G.R.R. Martin&amp;rsquo;s fantasy world where 2-4 (usually just 2) players build armies from different factions then compete to win a certain number of victory points. There are different game modes that determine how to achieve VPs, but generally killing your opponent&amp;rsquo;s troops will help.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
